<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Expert Sessions on hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/expert-sessions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Expert Sessions on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 12:08:09 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/expert-sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climb your Way Up to Senior Ruby Dev with Fabiano Beselga</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/expert-guest-sessions/expert-sessions-with-fabiano-beselga-april-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 12:08:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/expert-guest-sessions/expert-sessions-with-fabiano-beselga-april-20/</guid>
      <description>Climb your Way Up to Senior Ruby Dev with Fabiano Beselga Fabiano Beselga is a Staff Software Engineer with several years of experience in making a business successful through leadership and technology.
Fabiano was the CTO and cofounder of Magnetis, one of the fastest growing Brazilian fintech startups. He was the CTO of Shore, and is currently designing the technical career track as a Staff Engineer at Kaia Health.
In this session, we talked about how to Get to Senior as a mid-career Ruby Developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Thursdays Expert Session with Rafael França on Aug 5th</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-rafael-franca-aug-5th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 12:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-rafael-franca-aug-5th/</guid>
      <description>Rafael França is a Rails Core team member and Principal Engineer at Shopify, and he is working to define the future of Ruby and Rails.
Rafael explained how to get started with contributing to Ruby on Rails, fix a bug, navigate the Rails code base and contribute to open source projects as a beginner. He also answered questions from the community.
Open Source Thursdays is a project from hexdevs to make Open Source contributions more inclusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Enough Hotwire for Rails Developers with Chris Oliver</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-chris-oliver-oct-14th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-chris-oliver-oct-14th/</guid>
      <description>Chris Oliver is the founder of GoRails, JumpStart Rails, Hatchbox and RailsBytes. He is also one of the hosts of the Remote Ruby podcast.
Just Enough Hotwire with Chris Oliver Want to add some JavaScript sprinkles to your Rails app but don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to learn how to use Hotwire?
Not finding Hotwire intuitive and it&amp;rsquo;s taking you time (that you don&amp;rsquo;t have) to understand it?
How much of JS do you need to learn if you just want to write minimal code in JS?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TenderJIT: A JIT compiler for Ruby with Aaron Patterson (tenderlove)</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-aaron-patterson-sep-30th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-aaron-patterson-sep-30th/</guid>
      <description>TenderJIT: A Pure Ruby JIT Compiler for Ruby Aaron Patterson (@tenderlove) joined our livestream as an expert guest on September 30th, 2021.
Aaron Patterson is a Senior Staff Engineer working at Shopify where he is focusing on Ruby core and Rails core development. Besides his achievements in software (which are both numerous and great), he is known for his humility, kindness, and accomplishments in the field of bio-writing.
Make sure to follow his Twitter account to keep up on all of his thoughtful insights and pearls of wisdom such as &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s Always Friday Somewhere!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
