<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Expert Sessions on hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/expert-sessions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Expert Sessions on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 12:56:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/expert-sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Thursdays Expert Session with Rafael França on Aug 5th</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-rafael-franca-aug-5th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 12:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-rafael-franca-aug-5th/</guid>
      <description>Rafael França is a Rails Core team member and Principal Engineer at Shopify, and he is working to define the future of Ruby and Rails.
Rafael explained how to get started with contributing to Ruby on Rails, fix a bug, navigate the Rails code base and contribute to open source projects as a beginner. He also answered questions from the community.
Open Source Thursdays is a project from hexdevs to make Open Source contributions more inclusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Enough Hotwire for Rails Developers with Chris Oliver (Oct 14th @ 2 PM PT)</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-chris-oliver-oct-14th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-chris-oliver-oct-14th/</guid>
      <description>Just Enough Hotwire for Rails Developers On October 14th at 2 PM PT, Chris Oliver (GoRails) will join our livestream as an expert guest. RSVP here.
Agenda Want to add some JavaScript sprinkles to your Rails app but don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to learn how to use Hotwire?
Let&amp;rsquo;s learn just enough Hotwire for Rails developers.
We are still working on the finalized agenda and the requirements for this session, stay tuned!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TenderJIT: A JIT compiler for Ruby with Aaron Patterson (tenderlove)</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-aaron-patterson-sep-30th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-aaron-patterson-sep-30th/</guid>
      <description>TenderJIT: A Pure Ruby JIT Compiler for Ruby Aaron Patterson (@tenderlove) joined our livestream as an expert guest on September 30th, 2021.
Aaron Patterson is a Senior Staff Engineer working at Shopify where he is focusing on Ruby core and Rails core development. Besides his achievements in software (which are both numerous and great), he is known for his humility, kindness, and accomplishments in the field of bio-writing.
Make sure to follow his Twitter account to keep up on all of his thoughtful insights and pearls of wisdom such as &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s Always Friday Somewhere!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
