<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>ruby on hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/ruby/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ruby on hexdevs</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.hexdevs.com/images/opengraph/hexdevs_logo.png</url>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/images/opengraph/hexdevs_logo.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 13:56:58 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/ruby/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>4 Strategies To Remove Dead Code from your Ruby App</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-remove-dead-code-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 13:56:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-remove-dead-code-ruby/</guid>
      <description>How much does it cost you to carry dead code? How do you find and remove zombie Ruby code? Use these 4 strategies to kill out all the dead code in your Ruby application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Thor Ruby Required Options</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/thor-ruby-options-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 13:21:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/thor-ruby-options-testing/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of tutorials for building a CLI with Thor from scratch, but there aren&amp;#39;t a lot of them on how to test Thor, especially covering scenarios such as required options. Learn how to test Thor Ruby options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Open Source with Richard Schneeman (@schneems)</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-open-source-with-richard-schneeman-schneems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 13:47:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-open-source-with-richard-schneeman-schneems/</guid>
      <description>What does lurking and flossing have to do with contributing to open source? It&amp;#39;s all about sustaining tiny habits. Learn how to use tiny habits to go from coder to contributor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does the Faker Ruby Gem Work?</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/faker-ruby-vitor-oliveira-open-source-thursdays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 16:58:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/faker-ruby-vitor-oliveira-open-source-thursdays/</guid>
      <description>How does the Faker Ruby gem work? How do you contribute to an Open Source Ruby project? Know exactly how by watching us do it live!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide: Quickly Debug a Ruby Gem with Pry and Git Bisect</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/debug-third-party-ruby-gem-with-pry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 16:21:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/debug-third-party-ruby-gem-with-pry/</guid>
      <description>A quick guide to help you debug a Third-Party Ruby Gem using `bundle open`, `pry`, and `git bisect`.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Ruby Developers Don’t Ask for Advice. They Do This And Build A Reputation As a Result</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/smart-ruby-developers-dont-ask-for-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 12:48:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/smart-ruby-developers-dont-ask-for-advice/</guid>
      <description>Want to find out for sure whether you’re moving up the Engineering Ladder anytime soon or not? Instead of asking for advice, ask for Instructive Feedback. Here&amp;#39;s how.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>216&#43; Ruby on Rails Open Source Applications You Can Use as a Reference</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/massive-list-of-open-source-ruby-on-rails-applications-you-can-use-as-a-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 13:11:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/massive-list-of-open-source-ruby-on-rails-applications-you-can-use-as-a-reference/</guid>
      <description>Have no idea how to implement a new Ruby on Rails feature? Or a Rails model? A migration? How to write a test? Here&amp;#39;s how to effectively use 200&#43; Ruby on Rails Applications as a reference for implementing the most common things you need as a Ruby developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find your Ruby Software Career Path with Mina Slater</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-software-engineer-career-path-mina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 16:40:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-software-engineer-career-path-mina/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever reflected on your career goals as a Software Developer? How often do you talk with someone who’s doing the kind of work you want to be doing? Find out how Mina Slater created her own role by taking advantage of her theater management background and expanding the impact of her work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Code Quality with Ernesto Tagwerker</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-code-quality-ernesto-tagwerker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 10:07:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-code-quality-ernesto-tagwerker/</guid>
      <description>Are you working on Ruby on Rails Applications that are constantly on fire, overwhelmed by technical debt? Instead of being a firefighter, what if you could be a happy programmer again? Listen and learn exactly how to measure tech debt and take the right steps to immediately improve code quality!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Enough Hotwire with Chris Oliver</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/hotwire-rails-chris-oliver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 21:55:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/hotwire-rails-chris-oliver/</guid>
      <description>An introduction to Hotwire with Chris Oliver, from GoRails. Hotwire is the new way of making AJAX requests on Ruby on Rails. Learn how to build JavaScript-less Rails with turbo streams, Stimulus, and form_with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tender Introduction to Ruby Internals with TenderJIT</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-just-in-time-compiler-tenderjit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 16:25:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-just-in-time-compiler-tenderjit/</guid>
      <description>A class on Ruby Internals and TenderJIT. Aaron Patterson (tenderlove) joined us on an Open Source Thursdays Expert Guest session to teach you about compilers, interpreters, and how to contribute to TenderJIT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Improve Code Quality on a Ruby on Rails Application</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/code-quality-ruby-on-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:45:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/code-quality-ruby-on-rails/</guid>
      <description>Taking ages to deliver small changes? Constantly sacrificing code quality? Is it possible to ever pay off tech debt? Yes, it is! Learn which Ruby code quality tools you can use to perform static code analysis and improve code quality. This post is a summary of Ernesto Tagwerker&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;Trapped in the Tar Pit?&amp;#39; talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> International Pricing for Ruby and Rails Books and Courses</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-courses-purchasing-power-parity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 17:40:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-courses-purchasing-power-parity/</guid>
      <description>Living in a country whose currency is undervalued, which makes it hard for you to afford a course priced in US dollars? Here&amp;#39;s a list of resources that offer discounts for Ruby and Rails developers who earn a local wage (outside of the US). The list includes one-time fee and monthly subscriptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Learn the Syntax of a Programming Language When You Know How to Code</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-learn-programming-language-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:34:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-learn-programming-language-syntax/</guid>
      <description>Do you have a hard time learning the syntax of a new programming language, even though you know how to code? Here&amp;#39;s a quick knowledge transfer exercise to help you learn Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Ruby on Rails Best Practices With One Exercise</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/learn-ruby-best-practices-with-one-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:29:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/learn-ruby-best-practices-with-one-exercise/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;#39;re craving some squeaky-clean code, but all you have for lunch every day is a big bowl of legacy spaghetti code. Here&amp;#39;s one way to change that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New job, new codebase. How do you even get started?</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/new-job-new-codebase-how-to-get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:25:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/new-job-new-codebase-how-to-get-started/</guid>
      <description>Are you joining a new company, and the codebase is massive and scary? Are you freaking out because you don&amp;#39;t even know where or how to get started? What if you could feel comfortable collaborating with your new team, and confidently navigate any codebase? Here is a list of strategies to help you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Pry Debug in 5 minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/pry-debug-in-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 19:22:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/pry-debug-in-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Whether you&amp;#39;re new to Pry or not, there are so many commands to learn! Get Started with Pry in 5 minutes and save hours of work next time you have to debug your code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
