<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ruby on rails on hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/ruby-on-rails/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ruby on rails on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 10:07:55 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/ruby-on-rails/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Code Quality with Ernesto Tagwerker</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-code-quality-ernesto-tagwerker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 10:07:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-code-quality-ernesto-tagwerker/</guid>
      <description>Are you working on Ruby on Rails Applications that are constantly on fire, overwhelmed by technical debt? Instead of being a firefighter, what if you could be a happy programmer again?
Listen and learn exactly how to measure tech debt and take the right steps to immediately improve code quality!
About our guest Ernesto Tagwerker is the founder &amp;amp; CTO at FastRuby.io &amp;amp; OmbuLabs. He is the maintainer of database_cleaner, bundler_leak, next_rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Enough Hotwire with Chris Oliver</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/hotwire-rails-chris-oliver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 21:55:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/hotwire-rails-chris-oliver/</guid>
      <description>Chris Oliver is the founder of GoRails, JumpStart Rails, Hatchbox and RailsBytes. He is also one of the hosts of the Remote Ruby podcast.
Chris showed us how to get started with Hotwire, how to inspect turbo streams. He also answered some questions from the audience, including how to migrate from Webpacker to jsbundling-rails, Websockets performance, and security.
   
Is Hotwire going to become popular? Chris says is going to take a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Improve Code Quality on a Ruby on Rails Application</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/code-quality-ruby-on-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:45:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/code-quality-ruby-on-rails/</guid>
      <description>Does it take forever to ship even small features on the codebase you&amp;rsquo;re working on? Is the code hard to understand and maintain? Are projects always running over budget? Are you constantly sacrificing code quality and not paying down technical debt?
When you change one feature, does another completely unrelated part of your app stop working? New bugs appear, even though tests never break? 🥵
Those are signs that you are suffering from working on a codebase with low code quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> International Pricing for Ruby and Rails Books and Courses</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-courses-purchasing-power-parity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 17:40:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-courses-purchasing-power-parity/</guid>
      <description>Are you looking for courses, training, and resources to improve your Ruby and Ruby on Rails skills, but you are not being paid in US dollars?
Most Ruby and Ruby on Rails books and courses are priced in US dollars. When you can&amp;rsquo;t afford them just because the country you live in has an undervalued currency compared to the dollar, it makes it difficult to invest in your education.
There are many free options you probably already know about, and you&amp;rsquo;re already using them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Learn the Syntax of a Programming Language When You Know How to Code</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-learn-programming-language-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:34:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-learn-programming-language-syntax/</guid>
      <description>Are you having a hard time picking up the syntax of a new programming language, even though you know how to code?
You&amp;rsquo;re new to Ruby, and people say it&amp;rsquo;s an easy language, but you find the syntax difficult to understand.
You know a bit of Javascript, Python, Java, or any other language. But Ruby seems like alien technology to you.
By the end of this post, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a tool to help you transfer your knowledge of [INSERT PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE HERE] to Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Ruby on Rails Best Practices With One Exercise</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/learn-ruby-best-practices-with-one-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:29:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/learn-ruby-best-practices-with-one-exercise/</guid>
      <description>You want to write smooth professional-looking code.
You&amp;rsquo;re craving some squeaky-clean code. But all you have for lunch every day is a big bowl of legacy spaghetti code.
You consider yourself a decent developer, but you&amp;rsquo;re never sure how to organize a project. How to name things. Where some piece of business logic should live.
How can you become a Ruby on Rails expert if the code you read every day stinks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Contribute to Ruby on Rails</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-open-source-contribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 17:04:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-open-source-contribution/</guid>
      <description>Are you looking for an opportunity to get more experience as a developer? Make meaningful connections with the community? Learn the best practices on how to maintain a large codebase?
What if you could get that experience by contributing to an open source project like Rails?
If that sounds scary, don&amp;rsquo;t worry! We can help you!
By the end of this post, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn 5 ways to become a new Rails contributor, even if you are a beginner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Pry Debug in 5 minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/pry-debug-in-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 19:22:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/pry-debug-in-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>When you&amp;rsquo;re banging your head against the wall trying to fix a bug, the last thing you want is having to stop and learn how to use the debugging tool.
The last time this happened, you added require &#39;pry&#39; on a ruby file but quickly realized you didn&amp;rsquo;t know the available commands.
If only there was a way for you to quickly learn how to use Pry&amp;hellip; Well, there is now!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
