<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 19:46:20 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>12xstartup</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/12xstartup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 19:46:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/12xstartup/</guid>
      <description>Hey, Stefanni here! 👋
I am happy to share that I&amp;rsquo;ve joined the 12xstartup.com challenge! Starting November 1st, and I wanted to share a few things with you:
Goal My main goal is to work consistently, get feedback, and learn how to solve problems.
I may not get to do 12 projects, but I will try my best. Maybe focusing on one project for 2 months or so, I don&amp;rsquo;t know yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Independence Course</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/writing-financial-independence-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 14:21:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/writing-financial-independence-course/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve been following us for a while, you know we are super passionate about FIRE/financial independence.
Five years ago, we didn&amp;rsquo;t even know where our money was going. Our dream of moving abroad felt so far away: we didn&amp;rsquo;t have any money. But we knew we had to do something about it!
We made a promise: that we would never have problems with money anymore. We started budgeting, investing, and growing our net worth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shape Up: Stop Running in Circles and Ship Work that Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/shape-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 07:31:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/shape-up/</guid>
      <description>About Shape Up Shape Up is an agile product development approach used internally by Basecamp. It has three distinct phases:
 Shaping  The product strategy team writes a pitch that describes the problem that needs to be solved, giving as much detail as needed, and proposes a solution. The level of detail should be specific enough so that the team working on the project knows what to do. It should also leave enough room so the team can figure out the best way to build a solution that fits scope and budget constraints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 17:07:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/about/</guid>
      <description>About the hexdevs podcast, blog and team</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
