<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 11:50:02 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Perceptual Learning == More Ruby Experts?</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/rubyconf2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 11:50:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/rubyconf2021/</guid>
      <description>Hi, nice seeing you here!
Thanks for checking out Perceptual Learning == More Ruby experts?. This talk was first presented at RubyConf2021.
You can find the slides and the resources mentioned in this talk below:
 Slides 🖼️ Resources mentioned in this talk 📖  Introduction I am Stefanni. Here at hexdevs, I research, design and develop programs to help you become an expert developer.
Ever since I found out about Perceptual Learning in the book &amp;ldquo;Badass - Making users awesome&amp;rdquo;, from Kathy Sierra, I got really curious to learn more about the science behind Perceptual Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One last thing: Confirm your Subscription</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/confirm-subscription-expert-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 15:48:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/confirm-subscription-expert-session/</guid>
      <description>Now check your inbox! Check your inbox for an email to confirm your subscription. That&amp;rsquo;s the only way we can send you all the details and reminders for this event.
The email is coming from &amp;ldquo;hexdevs&amp;rdquo;. If you can&amp;rsquo;t find it in your inbox, or check your other tabs/spam folder.
Still can&amp;rsquo;t find it? Send a message to team@hexdevs.com and we&amp;rsquo;ll fix it for you.
See you in your inbox!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Contribute to Ruby on Rails</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-open-source-contribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 17:04:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-open-source-contribution/</guid>
      <description>Are you looking for an opportunity to get more experience as a developer? Make meaningful connections with the community? Learn the best practices on how to maintain a large codebase?
What if you could get that experience by contributing to an open source project like Rails?
If that sounds scary, don&amp;rsquo;t worry! We can help you!
By the end of this post, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn 5 ways to become a new Rails contributor, even if you are a beginner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One last thing: Check your email</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/confirm-your-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 16:03:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/confirm-your-subscription/</guid>
      <description>Now check your inbox! Check your inbox for an email to confirm your subscription.
The email is coming from &amp;ldquo;hexdevs&amp;rdquo;. If you can&amp;rsquo;t find it in your inbox, check your other tabs or the spam folder.
Still can&amp;rsquo;t find it? Send a message to team@hexdevs.com and we&amp;rsquo;ll fix it for you.
See you in your inbox!
-Stefanni &amp;amp; Thiago</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The hexdevs newsletter</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 17:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Join hundreds of developers who get the hexdevs newsletter delivered to their inboxes. A couple times per month, you&amp;rsquo;ll receive a letter with some cool things that we’ve created to help you become an expert developer, completely free of charge. ​
We can&amp;rsquo;t wait to send it to you! 📥
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>This is the hexdevs Code of Conduct In order to make sure this community can be home to everyone, we’ve put together a few guidelines.
We expect members to&amp;hellip; Practice kindness towards themselves and other members.
Behave in a professional manner.
Make the hexdevs community a welcoming, supportive and encouraging environment.
Cultivate compassion and practice unconditional positive regard as they are able and willing.
To ensure all our members feel safe and comfortable… hexdevs cares about creating an open and welcoming community, and we are committed to making membership a respectful and harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of gender, gender identity and expression, sex, sexual orientation, disability, neuro(a)typicality, physical appearance, body size, race, ethnicity, national origin, immigration status, age, political affiliation, or religion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Thursdays Expert Session with Rafael França on Aug 5th</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-rafael-franca-aug-5th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 12:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-rafael-franca-aug-5th/</guid>
      <description>Rafael França is a Rails Core team member and Principal Engineer at Shopify, and he is working to define the future of Ruby and Rails.
Rafael explained how to get started with contributing to Ruby on Rails, fix a bug, navigate the Rails code base and contribute to open source projects as a beginner. He also answered questions from the community.
Open Source Thursdays is a project from hexdevs to make Open Source contributions more inclusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re in!</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 10:17:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for signing up. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have you here! 🎉
The Joy of Missing Out 😊 Here are some cool things we&amp;rsquo;ve created to help you become an expert developer.
📺 Want to become an expert Open Source Contributor? Watch How to Contribute to Ruby on Rails with Rafael França.
🐞 Want to improve your debugging skills in 5 minutes? Read Getting Started with Pry Debug in 5 minutes and grab your Pry Cheat Sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why no one reads your tech blog and how to fix that</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-no-one-reads-your-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 18:37:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-no-one-reads-your-blog/</guid>
      <description>You have a technical blog and you might have built it from scratch.
You wrote a bunch of great tutorials. Your posts are perfect. You are a smart person and you want to show your developer expertise.
There is only one problem: no one is reading what you write.
Why?
Do you want to know the answer? It&amp;rsquo;s going to hurt.
Here it goes:
&amp;ldquo;No one cares about you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Pry Debug in 5 minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/pry-debug-in-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 19:22:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/pry-debug-in-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>When you&amp;rsquo;re banging your head against the wall trying to fix a bug, the last thing you want is having to stop and learn how to use the debugging tool.
The last time this happened, you added require &#39;pry&#39; on a ruby file but quickly realized you didn&amp;rsquo;t know the available commands. What&amp;rsquo;s that noise? Oh, it&amp;rsquo;s the sound of more frustration being added to your day!
If only there was a way for you to quickly learn how to use Pry&amp;hellip; Well, there is now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hexdevs Watch Party</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/watch-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 20:28:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/watch-party/</guid>
      <description>Remember all those amazing tech talks sitting on your Watch Later list? Sounds more like a Never Watch list, right? ⌛🤭🤷‍♀️
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to watch a tech talk and hang out with other devs, then join the hexdevs Watch Party!
We host online interactive workshops with guided questions to help you effectively learn from the talk. It&amp;rsquo;s fun and you get to engage in a discussion with other devs about the topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Thursdays</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 12:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays-project/</guid>
      <description>Did you always want to contribute to Open Source projects but can&amp;rsquo;t get past getting overwhelmed and scared when looking at a big project just by yourself?
Open Source Thursdays is one of our projects where we aim to contribute to Open Source projects by doing live stream sessions.
The initial plan was to contribute to Ruby on Rails and to do everything live, with little or no preparation in advance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the Leap Into Entrepreneurship With Monica Lent</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/taking-the-leap-into-entrepreneurship-with-monica-lent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 12:50:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/taking-the-leap-into-entrepreneurship-with-monica-lent/</guid>
      <description>Monica Lent is a software engineer and entrepreneur. She decided to quit her job and bootstrap Affilimate full-time. She also created Blogging for Devs, a paid community to help developers grow their technical blogs with SEO.
  Apple Podcasts | Spotify
Show Notes  Monica Lent&amp;rsquo;s website Affilimate Blogging for Devs Monica&amp;rsquo;s Income Report Amy Hoy&amp;rsquo;s post about content marketing    Transcript Stefanni Brasil: [00:00:10] Our guest today is Monica Lent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unusual Tech Jobs with Brian Hall</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unusual-tech-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 22:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unusual-tech-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Brian David Hall is an expert in conversion optimization. He&amp;rsquo;s a software engineer by training, runs his own company, and is the host of the SaaS Experiments Podcast, where he talks to other experts in growth marketing. We talked about the unusual tech jobs he&amp;rsquo;s had that helped him learn other skills beyond coding.
  Apple Podcasts | Spotify
You can use your skills in other areas like Marketing and Sales to transition to a tech job instead of throwing away your current expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Michael Lynch Left His Job at Google to Become a Solo Founder</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-michael-lynch-left-his-job-at-google-to-become-a-solo-founder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 10:28:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-michael-lynch-left-his-job-at-google-to-become-a-solo-founder/</guid>
      <description>Michael Lynch is a software developer and blogger. He used to work as a software engineer at Google, but he decided to quit and now he&amp;rsquo;s a solo founder, and blogs about his experience.
Michael has recently launched the course Hit The Front Page of Hacker News Course. The course teaches everything he has learned about Hacker News after getting many of his original blog posts to hit the front page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing a Micro-SaaS to 30K MRR and 20K Users with DelightChat</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/grow-micro-saas-to-30k-per-month-delightchat-episode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 09:04:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/grow-micro-saas-to-30k-per-month-delightchat-episode/</guid>
      <description>We had a great time chatting with Preetam Nath and Sankalp Jonna, the co-founders of SuperLemon and DelightChat.
They started a micro-SaaS in 2019. After about 14 months, they grew the monthly recurring revenue to $30,000. More than 20,000 merchants are using their product on the Shopify App Store, which is completely insane!
DelightChat is a customer support tool for small and medium-sized e-commerces.
The great thing about their story is that they&amp;rsquo;re not just building a business, but building a life on top of that business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 17:07:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/about/</guid>
      <description>About hexdevs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Enough Hotwire for Rails Developers with Chris Oliver</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-chris-oliver-oct-14th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-chris-oliver-oct-14th/</guid>
      <description>Chris Oliver is the founder of GoRails, JumpStart Rails, Hatchbox and RailsBytes. He is also one of the hosts of the Remote Ruby podcast.
Just Enough Hotwire with Chris Oliver Want to add some JavaScript sprinkles to your Rails app but don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to learn how to use Hotwire?
Not finding Hotwire intuitive and it&amp;rsquo;s taking you time (that you don&amp;rsquo;t have) to understand it?
How much of JS do you need to learn if you just want to write minimal code in JS?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TenderJIT: A JIT compiler for Ruby with Aaron Patterson (tenderlove)</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-aaron-patterson-sep-30th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-aaron-patterson-sep-30th/</guid>
      <description>TenderJIT: A Pure Ruby JIT Compiler for Ruby Aaron Patterson (@tenderlove) joined our livestream as an expert guest on September 30th, 2021.
Aaron Patterson is a Senior Staff Engineer working at Shopify where he is focusing on Ruby core and Rails core development. Besides his achievements in software (which are both numerous and great), he is known for his humility, kindness, and accomplishments in the field of bio-writing.
Make sure to follow his Twitter account to keep up on all of his thoughtful insights and pearls of wisdom such as &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s Always Friday Somewhere!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
