<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 17:40:46 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Check your email</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/confirm-your-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 16:03:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/confirm-your-subscription/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! Please check your inbox to confirm your subscription: The email is coming from &amp;ldquo;hexdevs&amp;rdquo;. If you can&amp;rsquo;t find it in your inbox, check your other tabs or the spam folder.
Still can&amp;rsquo;t find it? Send a message to team@hexdevs.com and we&amp;rsquo;ll fix it for you.
See you in your inbox!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 17:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Get updates from the hexdevs team right in your inbox We don&amp;rsquo;t send spam and you can unsubscribe at any time.
We will send you a couple of emails per month to let you know about new blog posts, podcast episodes, next events, lives, workshops, watch parties.
See you inside 📥
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>This is the hexdevs Code of Conduct In order to make sure this community can be home to everyone, we’ve put together a few guidelines.
We expect members… Be kind to each other, and to yourself.
Create opportunities to collaborate with one another, and invite others to do so.
Take care of our space as if it’s your home (or better).
Leave spaces better than you found them.
Encourage others in their endeavors, and respect each other’s privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Thursdays Expert Session with Rafael França on Aug 5th</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-rafael-franca-aug-5th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 12:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-rafael-franca-aug-5th/</guid>
      <description>Rafael França is a Rails Core team member and Principal Engineer at Shopify, and he is working to define the future of Ruby and Rails.
Rafael explained how to get started with contributing to Ruby on Rails, fix a bug, navigate the Rails code base and contribute to open source projects as a beginner. He also answered questions from the community.
Open Source Thursdays is a project from hexdevs to make Open Source contributions more inclusive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re in!</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 10:17:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for signing up. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have you here! 🎉
The Joy of Missing Out 😊 Here are some cool things we&amp;rsquo;ve created to help you become an expert developer.
📺 Want to become an expert Open Source Contributor? Watch How to Contribute to Ruby on Rails with Rafael França.
🐞 Want to improve your debugging skills in 5 minutes? Read Getting Started with Pry Debug in 5 minutes and grab your Pry Cheat Sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why no one reads your tech blog and how to fix that</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-no-one-reads-your-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 18:37:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-no-one-reads-your-blog/</guid>
      <description>You have a technical blog and you might have built it from scratch.
You wrote a bunch of great tutorials. Your posts are perfect. You are a smart person and you want to show your developer expertise.
There is only one problem: no one is reading what you write.
Why?
Do you want to know the answer? It&amp;rsquo;s going to hurt.
Here it goes:
&amp;ldquo;No one cares about you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Pry Debug in 5 minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/pry-debug-in-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 19:22:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/pry-debug-in-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>When you&amp;rsquo;re banging your head against the wall trying to fix a bug, the last thing you want is having to stop and learn how to use the debugging tool.
The last time this happened, you added require &#39;pry&#39; on a ruby file but quickly realized you didn&amp;rsquo;t know the available commands. What&amp;rsquo;s that noise? Oh, it&amp;rsquo;s the sound of more frustration being added to your day!
If only there was a way for you to quickly learn how to use Pry&amp;hellip; Well, there is now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hexdevs Watch Party</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/watch-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 20:28:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/watch-party/</guid>
      <description>Do you know all the amazing tech talks sitting on your Watch later list? Sounds more like a Never Watch list, right? ⌛🤭🤷‍♀️
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to watch a tech talk and hang out with other devs, then join the hexdevs Watch Party!
We host online interactive workshops with guided questions to help you effectively learn from the talk. It&amp;rsquo;s fun and you get to engage in a discussion with other devs about the topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Thursdays</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 12:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays-project/</guid>
      <description>What is Open Source Thursdays? Did you always want to contribute to Rails but can&amp;rsquo;t get past getting overwhelmed and scared when looking at a big project by yourself?
That&amp;rsquo;s how we felt! We thought, why not do it live so other people can join us?
Neither of us has done this before. The plan is to get there and do everything live, no preparing in advance. Just the real work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the Leap Into Entrepreneurship With Monica Lent</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/taking-the-leap-into-entrepreneurship-with-monica-lent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 12:50:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/taking-the-leap-into-entrepreneurship-with-monica-lent/</guid>
      <description>Monica Lent is a software engineer and entrepreneur. She decided to quit her job and bootstrap Affilimate full-time. She also created Blogging for Devs, a paid community to help developers grow their technical blogs with SEO.
  Apple Podcasts | Spotify
Show Notes  Monica Lent&amp;rsquo;s website Affilimate Blogging for Devs Monica&amp;rsquo;s Income Report Amy Hoy&amp;rsquo;s post about content marketing    Transcript Stefanni Brasil: [00:00:10] Our guest today is Monica Lent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unusual Tech Jobs with Brian Hall</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unusual-tech-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 22:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unusual-tech-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Brian David Hall is an expert in conversion optimization. He&amp;rsquo;s a software engineer by training, runs his own company, and is the host of the SaaS Experiments Podcast, where he talks to other experts in growth marketing. We talked about the unusual tech jobs he&amp;rsquo;s had that helped him learn other skills beyond coding.
  Apple Podcasts | Spotify
You can use your skills in other areas like Marketing and Sales to transition to a tech job instead of throwing away your current expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Michael Lynch Left His Job at Google to Become a Solo Founder</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-michael-lynch-left-his-job-at-google-to-become-a-solo-founder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 10:28:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-michael-lynch-left-his-job-at-google-to-become-a-solo-founder/</guid>
      <description>Michael Lynch is a software developer and blogger. He used to work as a software engineer at Google, but he decided to quit and now he&amp;rsquo;s a solo founder, and blogs about his experience.
Michael has recently launched the course Hit The Front Page of Hacker News Course. The course teaches everything he has learned about Hacker News after getting many of his original blog posts to hit the front page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing a Micro-SaaS to 30K MRR and 20K Users with DelightChat</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/grow-micro-saas-to-30k-per-month-delightchat-episode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 09:04:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/grow-micro-saas-to-30k-per-month-delightchat-episode/</guid>
      <description>We had a great time chatting with Preetam Nath and Sankalp Jonna, the co-founders of SuperLemon and DelightChat.
They started a micro-SaaS in 2019. After about 14 months, they grew the monthly recurring revenue to $30,000. More than 20,000 merchants are using their product on the Shopify App Store, which is completely insane!
DelightChat is a customer support tool for small and medium-sized e-commerces.
The great thing about their story is that they&amp;rsquo;re not just building a business, but building a life on top of that business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 17:07:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/about/</guid>
      <description>About hexdevs</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
