<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on hexdevs</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.hexdevs.com/images/opengraph/hexdevs_logo.png</url>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/images/opengraph/hexdevs_logo.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 13:56:58 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>4 Strategies To Remove Dead Code from your Ruby App</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/removing-dead-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 13:56:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/removing-dead-code/</guid>
      <description>How much does it cost you to carry dead code? How do you find and remove zombie Ruby code? Use these 4 strategies to kill out all the dead code in your Ruby application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Technical Wealth and Improving Legacy Code with M. Scott Ford</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/building-technical-wealth-legacy-code-m-scott-ford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 14:44:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/building-technical-wealth-legacy-code-m-scott-ford/</guid>
      <description>Are you working on Ruby on Rails Applications that are constantly on fire, overwhelmed by technical debt? What if you were building Technical Wealth instead? Learn which tools &amp;amp; strategies to work with legacy code effectively, remove dead code, and leave tech debt behind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Thor Ruby Required Options</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/thor-ruby-options-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2022 13:21:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/thor-ruby-options-testing/</guid>
      <description>There are lots of tutorials for building a CLI with Thor from scratch, but there aren&amp;#39;t a lot of them on how to test Thor, especially covering scenarios such as required options. Learn how to test Thor Ruby options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Open Source with Richard Schneeman (@schneems)</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-open-source-with-richard-schneeman-schneems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 13:47:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-open-source-with-richard-schneeman-schneems/</guid>
      <description>What does lurking and flossing have to do with contributing to open source? It&amp;#39;s all about sustaining tiny habits. Learn how to use tiny habits to go from coder to contributor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to RSpec a Jbuilder response from a Rails JSON API</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/rails-jbuilder-json-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 07:09:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/rails-jbuilder-json-api/</guid>
      <description>Want to write a Rails API controller test and make sure it includes exactly what your Jbuilder serializer returns? You need to enable `render_views`. Learn why in this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How does the Faker Ruby Gem Work?</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/faker-ruby-vitor-oliveira-open-source-thursdays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 16:58:54 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/faker-ruby-vitor-oliveira-open-source-thursdays/</guid>
      <description>How does the Faker Ruby gem work? How do you contribute to an Open Source Ruby project? Know exactly how by watching us do it live!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Guide] How to Contribute to Ruby on Rails</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/contribute-ruby-on-rails-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 10:08:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/contribute-ruby-on-rails-guide/</guid>
      <description>Are you looking for an opportunity to get more experience as a Ruby on Rails developer? Make meaningful connections with the community? Learn the best practices on how to maintain a large codebase such as Ruby on Rails? What if you had a step by step guide on how to get started? Get your free guide and start contributing to Rails today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Surprising Way to Become a Senior Software Developer with Caroline Salib</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/get-to-senior-developer-caroline-salib/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 18:06:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/get-to-senior-developer-caroline-salib/</guid>
      <description>What to do when you&amp;#39;ve been doing one technical course after the other, and still not making the jump to Senior? What are the non-obvious skills you need to be promoted to Senior? Listen to our conversation with Caroline Salib on how to identify the non-obvious skills to get promoted to Senior Software Developer -- and it&amp;#39;s not another technical course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What books on Ruby should I read when trying to move from Junior to Intermediate Developer?</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/books-level-up-junior-to-intermediate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 16:03:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/books-level-up-junior-to-intermediate/</guid>
      <description>Want to avoid going through lots of frustration when self-learning Ruby or any other programming skills? In this post, I&amp;#39;m going to share a few tools for your self-learning technical practice toolkit and get the most out of your continuous technical practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I need to join Get to Senior</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 11:24:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/boss/</guid>
      <description>A letter you can copy/paste and send to your boss for buying Get to Senior Cohort for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Clean Order By Case Query with Arel on Rails</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-write-order-by-case-query-with-arel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 15:48:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-write-order-by-case-query-with-arel/</guid>
      <description>Do you need to write a complicated order by query on your Rails app? Here&amp;#39;s how you can write an Order By Case Statement using Arel and keep things clean and reusable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guide: Quickly Debug a Ruby Gem with Pry and Git Bisect</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/debug-third-party-ruby-gem-with-pry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 16:21:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/debug-third-party-ruby-gem-with-pry/</guid>
      <description>A quick guide to help you debug a Third-Party Ruby Gem using `bundle open`, `pry`, and `git bisect`.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Ruby Developers Don’t Ask for Advice. They Do This And Build A Reputation As a Result</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/smart-ruby-developers-dont-ask-for-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 12:48:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/smart-ruby-developers-dont-ask-for-advice/</guid>
      <description>Want to find out for sure whether you’re moving up the Engineering Ladder anytime soon or not? Instead of asking for advice, ask for Instructive Feedback. Here&amp;#39;s how.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>216&#43; Ruby on Rails Open Source Applications You Can Use as a Reference</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/massive-list-of-open-source-ruby-on-rails-applications-you-can-use-as-a-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 13:11:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/massive-list-of-open-source-ruby-on-rails-applications-you-can-use-as-a-reference/</guid>
      <description>Have no idea how to implement a new Ruby on Rails feature? Or a Rails model? A migration? How to write a test? Here&amp;#39;s how to effectively use 200&#43; Ruby on Rails Applications as a reference for implementing the most common things you need as a Ruby developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climb your Way Up to Senior Ruby Dev with Fabiano Beselga</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/expert-guest-sessions/expert-sessions-with-fabiano-beselga-april-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 12:08:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/expert-guest-sessions/expert-sessions-with-fabiano-beselga-april-20/</guid>
      <description>How do you get promoted to Senior level? How do Engineering paths work? Fabiano Beselga answered the most common questions about Ruby career promotions, climbing up the Engineering Ladder, and how to get to Senior level. Watch the conversation now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find your Ruby Software Career Path with Mina Slater</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-software-engineer-career-path-mina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 16:40:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-software-engineer-career-path-mina/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever reflected on your career goals as a Software Developer? How often do you talk with someone who’s doing the kind of work you want to be doing? Find out how Mina Slater created her own role by taking advantage of her theater management background and expanding the impact of her work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create and Deliver a Technical Talk as a Software Developer</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/public-speaking-tips-for-software-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 12:57:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/public-speaking-tips-for-software-developers/</guid>
      <description>Wanna deliver a technical talk but don&amp;#39;t know what to talk about, how to get started, and how to tackle public speaking as a software developer? Learn how to create a short tech talk following a step-by-step recipe that only takes 20 minutes. Plus, public speaking tips, how to reuse the content later, and keep practicing your public speaking skills!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 1 Mistake Keeping Mid-Career Developers Stuck in a Loop</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/one-mistake-keeping-mid-level-developers-stuck-in-a-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 10:59:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/one-mistake-keeping-mid-level-developers-stuck-in-a-loop/</guid>
      <description>Are you stuck as a mid-level developer? Trying to keep practicing after work, but don&amp;#39;t feel like you&amp;#39;re learning anything? What if you knew the next steps for you to make the jump to Senior? Learn how to save time and energy by doing one thing differently today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get to Senior Crash Course</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/senior-crash-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 11:31:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/senior-crash-course/</guid>
      <description>You’ve got the coding skills, you’ve got the experience. But haven’t been promoted to Senior yet? Stop waiting. Take the next step in your career with the (FREE) Get to Senior Email Crash Course. Get started now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unhappy as a Developer? How Not To Be Miserable with Dr. Randy Paterson</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unhappy-software-developers-randy-paterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 16:25:06 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unhappy-software-developers-randy-paterson/</guid>
      <description>Do you suffer from Slack notification anxiety? On-call schedules and deadlines giving you nightmares? Learn how to deal with conflict at work and in relationships with Dr. Randy Paterson, author of The Assertiveness Workbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Code Quality with Ernesto Tagwerker</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-code-quality-ernesto-tagwerker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 10:07:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-code-quality-ernesto-tagwerker/</guid>
      <description>Are you working on Ruby on Rails Applications that are constantly on fire, overwhelmed by technical debt? Instead of being a firefighter, what if you could be a happy programmer again? Listen and learn exactly how to measure tech debt and take the right steps to immediately improve code quality!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;I&#39;ve been stagnating as a mid-level Ruby on Rails developer&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/senior/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 17:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/senior/</guid>
      <description>Do you feel stuck in your Software Developer career, not sure what to do next? What if you were taking the next steps and building an amazing career for yourself? Take your career to the next level with Get to Senior!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;I&#39;ve been stagnating in my current position as a mid-level Ruby on Rails developer&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 17:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/workshop/</guid>
      <description>Get hands-on experience with designing and architecting production-grade Ruby applications in the Software Design Workshop. There is a limited number of seats. Get on the waitlist and save your spot now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Enough Hotwire with Chris Oliver</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/hotwire-rails-chris-oliver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 21:55:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/hotwire-rails-chris-oliver/</guid>
      <description>An introduction to Hotwire with Chris Oliver, from GoRails. Hotwire is the new way of making AJAX requests on Ruby on Rails. Learn how to build JavaScript-less Rails with turbo streams, Stimulus, and form_with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tender Introduction to Ruby Internals with TenderJIT</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-just-in-time-compiler-tenderjit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 16:25:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-just-in-time-compiler-tenderjit/</guid>
      <description>A class on Ruby Internals and TenderJIT. Aaron Patterson (tenderlove) joined us on an Open Source Thursdays Expert Guest session to teach you about compilers, interpreters, and how to contribute to TenderJIT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Expertise (Part II): A Better Way to Practice Ruby with Deliberate Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/perceptual-learning-programming-deliberate-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 16:35:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/perceptual-learning-programming-deliberate-practice/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean to be an expert? How do humans develop experts skills? What is the difference between being an experienced developer and an expert developer? To answer these questions, let&amp;#39;s learn from the latest research on the science of expertise and perceptual learning, and PL techniques to help you become a Ruby expert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Expertise (Part I): Introduction to Perceptual Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/perceptual-learning-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 16:21:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/perceptual-learning-introduction/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean to be an expert? How do humans develop experts skills? What is the difference between being an experienced developer and an expert developer? To answer these questions, let&amp;#39;s learn from the latest research on the science of expertise and perceptual learning, and PL techniques to help you become a Ruby expert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Developer Portfolio And Be Stuck Forever</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/build-a-developer-portfolio-get-stuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 13:47:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/build-a-developer-portfolio-get-stuck/</guid>
      <description>Have you spent months building a tech portfolio to get your first developer job, but not getting any results? That&amp;#39;s mainly because a portfolio is an endless project with no scope and no end-goal. It&amp;#39;s easy to get stuck forever. How about building trust instead?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Improve Code Quality on a Ruby on Rails Application</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/code-quality-ruby-on-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:45:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/code-quality-ruby-on-rails/</guid>
      <description>Taking ages to deliver small changes? Constantly sacrificing code quality? Is it possible to ever pay off tech debt? Yes, it is! Learn which Ruby code quality tools you can use to perform static code analysis and improve code quality. This post is a summary of Ernesto Tagwerker&amp;#39;s &amp;#39;Trapped in the Tar Pit?&amp;#39; talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> International Pricing for Ruby and Rails Books and Courses</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-courses-purchasing-power-parity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 17:40:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-courses-purchasing-power-parity/</guid>
      <description>Living in a country whose currency is undervalued, which makes it hard for you to afford a course priced in US dollars? Here&amp;#39;s a list of resources that offer discounts for Ruby and Rails developers who earn a local wage (outside of the US). The list includes one-time fee and monthly subscriptions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Learn the Syntax of a Programming Language When You Know How to Code</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-learn-programming-language-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:34:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/how-to-learn-programming-language-syntax/</guid>
      <description>Do you have a hard time learning the syntax of a new programming language, even though you know how to code? Here&amp;#39;s a quick knowledge transfer exercise to help you learn Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn Ruby on Rails Best Practices With One Exercise</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/learn-ruby-best-practices-with-one-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:29:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/learn-ruby-best-practices-with-one-exercise/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;#39;re craving some squeaky-clean code, but all you have for lunch every day is a big bowl of legacy spaghetti code. Here&amp;#39;s one way to change that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New job, new codebase. How do you even get started?</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/new-job-new-codebase-how-to-get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:25:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/new-job-new-codebase-how-to-get-started/</guid>
      <description>Are you joining a new company, and the codebase is massive and scary? Are you freaking out because you don&amp;#39;t even know where or how to get started? What if you could feel comfortable collaborating with your new team, and confidently navigate any codebase? Here is a list of strategies to help you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples of Successful Self-Taught Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/examples-successful-self-taught-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:19:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/examples-successful-self-taught-developers/</guid>
      <description>Feel like coding is not for you? You&amp;#39;re not alone. To give you a boost of inspiration, here&amp;#39;s a list of a few successful Rails developers that come from unusual backgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write Badass READMES for your Github projects</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/github-readme-examples-and-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:16:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/github-readme-examples-and-template/</guid>
      <description>Tips, examples and a template for writing simple yet useful Github READMEs for your projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unstuck Guide for Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unstuck-guide-for-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:03:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unstuck-guide-for-developers/</guid>
      <description>Feeling frustrated with everything you need to learn? Feel like things will never &amp;#39;click&amp;#39;? Try this surprisingly simple way to get unstuck as a developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dev With No Experience? Here&#39;s one way to get experience today.</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/first-ruby-dev-job-no-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 12:57:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/first-ruby-dev-job-no-experience/</guid>
      <description>Beep. Another rejection. You don&amp;#39;t have experience for an entry-level Ruby job. Worse: chirp, chirp, chirp. No replies at all. Are you tired of all of this? If you want to get real-world experience, apply this strategy to get different results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptual Learning == More Ruby Experts?</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/rubyconf2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 11:50:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/rubyconf2021/</guid>
      <description>What does it mean to be an expert? How do humans develop experts skills? What is the difference between being an experienced developer and an expert developer? To answer these questions, let&amp;#39;s learn from the latest research on the science of expertise and perceptual learning, and PL techniques to help you become a Ruby expert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TenderJIT: A JIT compiler for Ruby with Aaron Patterson (tenderlove)</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-aaron-patterson-sep-30th/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 11:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-aaron-patterson-sep-30th/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;#39;s work on a JIT compiler for Ruby that’s written in Ruby! We’re going to start building a JIT for Ruby from the ground up. First, we’ll learn how Ruby’s virtual machine works, then talk about the CPU itself. Finally we’ll start building a JIT for Ruby in Ruby. This session happened on September 30th, 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One last thing: Confirm your Subscription</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/confirm-subscription-expert-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 15:48:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/confirm-subscription-expert-session/</guid>
      <description>Confirm your Subscription to the Expert Session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Contribute to Ruby on Rails</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-open-source-contribution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 17:04:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-on-rails-open-source-contribution/</guid>
      <description>This post is a summary of the Open Source Thursdays - Expert Session with Rafael França. Learn how to get started, how to fix a bug, navigate the Ruby on Rails codebase and contribute to Open Source projects as a beginner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One last thing: Check your email</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/confirm-your-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 16:03:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/confirm-your-subscription/</guid>
      <description>Confirm Your Subscription</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hexdevs newsletter</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 17:40:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Do you want to become an expert Ruby developer? Sign up for the hexdevs newsletter!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 10:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>This is the hexdevs Code of Conduct. In order to make sure this community can be home to everyone, we’ve put together a few guidelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Thursdays Expert Session with Rafael França on Aug 5th</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-rafael-franca-aug-5th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 12:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-rafael-franca-aug-5th/</guid>
      <description>Contribute to Ruby on Rails with Rafael França, Rails Core team member, on August 5th</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You&#39;re in!</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 10:17:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>Thank you for signing up. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have you here! 🎉
The Joy of Missing Out 😊 Here are some cool things we&amp;rsquo;ve created to help you become an expert developer.
📕 Are you afraid you&#39;ll be stuck forever as a mid-level developer?# Sign up for the free Get to Senior Crash Course and take control of your career today!
🚀 Want to get your career to the next level?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why no one reads your tech blog and how to fix that</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-no-one-reads-your-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 18:37:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-no-one-reads-your-blog/</guid>
      <description>Why does no one read your blog? Do you want to know the answer? It&amp;#39;s going to hurt, but the truth it&amp;#39;s liberating!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Pry Debug in 5 minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/pry-debug-in-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 19:22:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/pry-debug-in-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Whether you&amp;#39;re new to Pry or not, there are so many commands to learn! Get Started with Pry in 5 minutes and save hours of work next time you have to debug your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hexdevs Watch Party</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/watch-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 20:28:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/watch-party/</guid>
      <description>Remember all those amazing tech talks sitting on your Watch Later list? Sounds more like a **Never Watch list**, right? ⌛🤭🤷‍♀️ So many great tech talks to learn from but you simply can&amp;#39;t find the time to watch them. Now you do!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Thursdays</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 12:56:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays-project/</guid>
      <description>Contributing to Ruby Open Source projects with hexdevs and Ruby Experts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking the Leap Into Entrepreneurship With Monica Lent</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/taking-the-leap-into-entrepreneurship-with-monica-lent/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 12:50:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/taking-the-leap-into-entrepreneurship-with-monica-lent/</guid>
      <description>Building profitable online businesses as a developer with Monica Lent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unusual Tech Jobs with Brian Hall</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unusual-tech-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 22:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unusual-tech-jobs/</guid>
      <description>Learning how to code on top of your existing skills will give you superpowers! Learn how to use your skills in other areas to land a developer job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Michael Lynch Left His Job at Google to Become a Solo Founder</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-michael-lynch-left-his-job-at-google-to-become-a-solo-founder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 10:28:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-michael-lynch-left-his-job-at-google-to-become-a-solo-founder/</guid>
      <description>Learn why Michael Lynch decided to quit his job at Google to run his own online businesses, his Financial Independence goals and the experience of launching an online course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grow a Micro-SaaS to 30K MRR with DelightChat</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/grow-micro-saas-to-30k-per-month-delightchat-episode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 09:04:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/grow-micro-saas-to-30k-per-month-delightchat-episode/</guid>
      <description>Learn how Preetam Nath and Sankalp Jonna, co-founders of DelightChat, built a Micro-SaaS on the Shopify App Store and grew it to 30K MRR and &#43;20K users in 14 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About us</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 17:07:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/about/</guid>
      <description>What is hexdevs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just Enough Hotwire for Rails Developers with Chris Oliver</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-chris-oliver-oct-14th/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/open-source-thursdays/expert-sessions-with-chris-oliver-oct-14th/</guid>
      <description>Learn Just enough Hotwire for Rails Developers with Chris Oliver (GoRails)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
