<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 12:08:09 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Climb your Way Up to Senior Ruby Dev with Fabiano Beselga</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/expert-guest-sessions/expert-sessions-with-fabiano-beselga-april-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 12:08:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/expert-guest-sessions/expert-sessions-with-fabiano-beselga-april-20/</guid>
      <description>Climb your Way Up to Senior Ruby Dev with Fabiano Beselga On April 20th at 10 AM Pacific Time (see in your timezone), Fabiano Beselga will join our Livestream as an expert guest.
👉 RSVP here
Fabiano Beselga is a Staff Software Engineer with several years of experience in making a business successful through leadership and technology.
Fabiano was the CTO and cofounder of Magnetis, one of the fastest growing Brazilian fintech startups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find your Ruby Software Career Path with Mina Slater</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-software-engineer-career-path-mina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 16:40:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-software-engineer-career-path-mina/</guid>
      <description>Often as developers, we believe we are supposed to know everything. Just figure everything by ourselves. As long as we get faster and better at coding, our careers will progress smoothly.
But if you ask around, you’ll notice that most people are feeling technically stuck, despite years of experience. If you ask for career advice, people will throw you an endless list of complex technical skills to master.
That’s not what you’ll find here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create and Deliver a Technical Talk as a Software Developer</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/public-speaking-tips-for-software-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 12:57:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/public-speaking-tips-for-software-developers/</guid>
      <description>Everyone says delivering a technical talk is a great opportunity to connect with people, build your reputation, create opportunities to grow your career. In one of the lessons of Get to Senior, we even recommend people to not simply don&amp;rsquo;t go to meetups&amp;hellip; but to talk at meetups!
But, when you finally decide to do it, the fear of tackling public speaking pops up. Is public speaking even a required skill for a Software Engineer?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unhappy as a Developer? How Not To Be Miserable with Dr. Randy Paterson</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unhappy-software-developers-randy-paterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 16:25:06 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unhappy-software-developers-randy-paterson/</guid>
      <description>Do you suffer from Slack notification anxiety? On-call schedules and deadlines giving you nightmares? Are your teammates nitpicking your code during code review?
Instead of quitting your job out of frustration and having to go through another round of technical interviews, what if you knew how to have a great relationship with your work?
Learn how to deal with imposter syndrome, unrealistic deadlines, and stop communicating passive-aggressively today! Communicate effectively with your team and finish the day feeling good about what you&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New job, new codebase. How do you even get started?</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/new-job-new-codebase-how-to-get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 13:25:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/new-job-new-codebase-how-to-get-started/</guid>
      <description>One of my readers asked:
 How do you get started when you join a new company? How do you add features to a codebase that is massive, scary, and completely new to you?
 The first day at your new developer job is just like the first day at a new school. 🚸
A sea of stranger&amp;rsquo;s faces watching your every move. Unfamiliar smells in the hallway.
Every chair is uncomfortable and makes weird noises when you sit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
