<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>code quality on hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/code-quality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in code quality on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 14:44:02 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/code-quality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Technical Wealth and Improving Legacy Code with M. Scott Ford</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/building-technical-wealth-legacy-code-m-scott-ford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 14:44:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/building-technical-wealth-legacy-code-m-scott-ford/</guid>
      <description>Listen to and watch our conversation with M. Scott Ford and learn how to build technical wealth, enjoy working with legacy code, tools, and strategies to remove dead code, and how thrive in a world of makers as a mender.
 
 Apple Podcasts | Spotify
   
About our guest M. Scott Ford is the Co-Founder &amp;amp; Chief Code Whisperer of Corgibytes, where he has quietly led a software maintenance revolution for the past decade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ruby Code Quality with Ernesto Tagwerker</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-code-quality-ernesto-tagwerker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 10:07:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-code-quality-ernesto-tagwerker/</guid>
      <description>Are you working on Ruby on Rails Applications that are constantly on fire, overwhelmed by technical debt?
Instead of being a firefighter, what if you could be a happy programmer again and &amp;ldquo;Escape the tar pit&amp;rdquo;?
Learn exactly how to measure tech debt and take the right steps to immediately improve code quality. Listen to our conversation with Ernesto Tagwerker (@etagwerker).
 
 Apple Podcasts | Spotify
About our guest Ernesto Tagwerker is the founder &amp;amp; CTO at FastRuby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Improve Code Quality on a Ruby on Rails Application</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/code-quality-ruby-on-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:45:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/code-quality-ruby-on-rails/</guid>
      <description>Does it take forever to ship even small features on the codebase you&amp;rsquo;re working on? Is the code hard to understand and maintain? Are projects always running over budget? Are you constantly sacrificing code quality and not paying down technical debt?
When you change one feature, does another completely unrelated part of your app stop working? New bugs appear, even though tests never break? 🥵
Those are signs that you are suffering from working on a codebase with low code quality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
