<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Perceptual Learning on hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/perceptual-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Perceptual Learning on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 16:35:31 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/perceptual-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Expertise: A Better Way to Practice Ruby with Deliberate Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/perceptual-learning-programming-deliberate-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 16:35:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/perceptual-learning-programming-deliberate-practice/</guid>
      <description>This article is the second part of the Science of Expertise series. Before reading along, read The Science of Expertise: introduction to Perceptual Learning. the resources mentioned in this series is also found at the end.
A Better Way to Practice Ruby: Deliberate Practice Perceptual Learning results are promising.
Unfortunately, no research has been made for programming yet. In this article, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn what we apply from what&amp;rsquo;s been published regarding Perceptual Learning in several domains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Science of Expertise: Introduction to Perceptual Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/perceptual-learning-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 16:21:38 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/perceptual-learning-introduction/</guid>
      <description>How do you become an expert? Why some Ruby developers can&amp;rsquo;t explain what they know? Why some developers don&amp;rsquo;t develop expert skills? What does it mean to be a Ruby expert?
To discuss these questions, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore Perceptual Learning (PL) research.
PL is a natural learning process that complements traditional Education. It accelerates expertise by speeding pattern recognition, intuition and fluency on a given subject.
Ever since I found out about Perceptual Learning in the book &amp;ldquo;Badass - Making users awesome&amp;rdquo;, from Kathy Sierra, I got really curious to learn more about the science behind Perceptual Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceptual Learning == More Ruby Experts?</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/rubyconf2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 11:50:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/rubyconf2021/</guid>
      <description>Hi, nice seeing you here!
Thanks for checking out Perceptual Learning == More Ruby experts? presented at RubyConf 2021.
  
You can find the slides and the resources mentioned in this talk below:
 Slides 🖼️ Resources mentioned in this talk 📖  The Science of Expertise series hexdevs team is working on some guides and exercises for practicing Ruby following the research principles shared here. A written format from this talk and new published articles can be found in the The Science of Expertise series ✍🏼</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
