<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>12xstartup on hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/12xstartup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 12xstartup on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 14:59:04 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/12xstartup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>12x Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/12xstartup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 15:00:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/12xstartup/</guid>
      <description>Hey, Stefanni here! 👋
I am happy to share that I&amp;rsquo;ve joined the 12xstartup.com challenge! Starting November 1st, and I wanted to share a few things with you:
Goal My main goal is to work consistently, get feedback, and learn how to solve problems.
I may not get to do 12 projects, but I will try my best. I will also continue writing on The Plant-Based Diet Club and creating content for the hexdevs podcast/blog :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dev to Founder Journey: Sales Safari on Shopify</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/sales-safari-on-shopify/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 14:59:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/sales-safari-on-shopify/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back to Dev to Founder!
In the first episode, I committed to sharing my Shopify market research findings and hopefully have chosen a problem to work on. Spoiler: I did not choose a problem yet but I have interesting data that will guide me into making this decision pretty soon!
Regarding The Plant-Based Diet Club, I am happy to share that the 5-Day Plant-based Diet Email Challenge is going to be launched this Saturday!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dev to Founder Journey: The beginning</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/my-dev-to-founder-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 12:05:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/my-dev-to-founder-journey/</guid>
      <description>What is Dev to Founder? 
Hey there!
I am Stefanni and Dev to Founder is a new project where I share my trajectory from being a developer to bootstrapping a business for the first time!
From never having sold anything online to getting my first paying customers.
Although I am sharing my lessons to help you with my experience, it&amp;rsquo;s also a public commitment to push myself to ship things.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
