<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 20:58:26 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Dev to Founder Journey: Start small. Build up. Keep Shipping.</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/dev-to-founder-05-spark-your-runway-with-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 20:58:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/dev-to-founder-05-spark-your-runway-with-fire/</guid>
      <description>In the previous episode, I shared why I decided to choose an audience that I belong to: Rails Developers. Recently, I took a small detour from my 30x500 journey. This detour is what I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking more about on this episode!
Let&amp;rsquo;s go!
Spark your Runway with FIRE Two weeks ago, I published a guide called Spark your Runway with FIRE! It&amp;rsquo;s a pay-what-you-want guide about building up your runway so you can go independent on your own products, sooner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dev to Founder Journey: Painstorming Results</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/dev-to-founder-04-painstorming-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 12:12:23 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/dev-to-founder-04-painstorming-results/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the 4th episode of Dev to Founder!
In the previous episode, I shared why I decided to choose an audience that I belong to. You can listen to the episode to learn more about this process.
My audience is Ruby Developers and I set the goal of doing Sales Safari/Painstorming sessions to explore what they need, want, and buy.
And that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I did!
Painstorming my audience watering holes Watering holes is a a term from 30x500 and it&amp;rsquo;s where your audience hangs out online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Michael Lynch Left His Job at Google to Become a Solo Founder</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-michael-lynch-left-his-job-at-google-to-become-a-solo-founder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 10:28:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/why-michael-lynch-left-his-job-at-google-to-become-a-solo-founder/</guid>
      <description>Michael Lynch is a software developer and blogger. He used to work as a software engineer at Google, but he decided to quit and now he&amp;rsquo;s a solo founder, and blogs about his experience.
Michael has recently launched the course Hit The Front Page of Hacker News Course. The course teaches everything he has learned about Hacker News after getting many of his original blog posts to hit the front page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dev to Founder Journey: Starting Again</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/dev-to-founder-03-starting-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 10:17:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/dev-to-founder-03-starting-again/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the 3rd episode of Dev to Founder!
In the latest episode, I forgot to share a huge milestone to me. As you may remember, I was doing CBT - Cognitive Behavior Therapy sessions. My therapist said I don&amp;rsquo;t need regular sessions anymore! This is big news and it&amp;rsquo;s incredible to see how much I learned with those sessions.
I still have lots of automatic negative thoughts but trust me, having the techniques that help me handle them on my own is priceless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growing a Micro-SaaS to 30K MRR and 20K Users with DelightChat</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/grow-micro-saas-to-30k-per-month-delightchat-episode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 09:04:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/grow-micro-saas-to-30k-per-month-delightchat-episode/</guid>
      <description>We had a great time chatting with Preetam Nath and Sankalp Jonna, the co-founders of SuperLemon and DelightChat.
They started a micro-SaaS in 2019. After about 14 months, they grew the monthly recurring revenue to $30,000. More than 20,000 merchants are using their product on the Shopify App Store, which is completely insane!
DelightChat is a customer support tool for small and medium-sized e-commerces.
The great thing about their story is that they&amp;rsquo;re not just building a business, but building a life on top of that business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dev to Founder Journey: Sales Safari on Shopify</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/sales-safari-on-shopify/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 14:59:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/sales-safari-on-shopify/</guid>
      <description>Welcome back to Dev to Founder!
In the first episode, I committed to sharing my Shopify market research findings and hopefully have chosen a problem to work on. Spoiler: I did not choose a problem yet but I have interesting data that will guide me into making this decision pretty soon!
Regarding The Plant-Based Diet Club, I am happy to share that the 5-Day Plant-based Diet Email Challenge is going to be launched this Saturday!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dev to Founder Journey: The beginning</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/my-dev-to-founder-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 12:05:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/my-dev-to-founder-journey/</guid>
      <description>What is Dev to Founder? 
Hey there!
I am Stefanni and Dev to Founder is a new project where I share my trajectory from being a developer to bootstrapping a business for the first time!
From never having sold anything online to getting my first paying customers.
Although I am sharing my lessons to help you with my experience, it&amp;rsquo;s also a public commitment to push myself to ship things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immigration to Canada via Express Entry</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/immigration-to-canada-via-express-entry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 12:14:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/immigration-to-canada-via-express-entry/</guid>
      <description>How to immigrate to Canada via Express Entry If you ever wanted to move to Canada, this is the time. Canada is planning on bringing more than 1 million immigrants in the next 3 years!
Dmitrii Pashtuskii is a digital nomad living in Bali, and he&amp;rsquo;s planning his Immigration process to Canada via Express Entry.
We recorded a podcast episode and Dimitrii asked us questions about moving to Canada because he wants to apply for a visa very soon:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shape Up: Stop Running in Circles and Ship Work that Matters</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/shape-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 07:31:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/shape-up/</guid>
      <description>About Shape Up Shape Up is an agile product development approach used internally by Basecamp. It has three distinct phases:
 Shaping  The product strategy team writes a pitch that describes the problem that needs to be solved, giving as much detail as needed, and proposes a solution. The level of detail should be specific enough so that the team working on the project knows what to do. It should also leave enough room so the team can figure out the best way to build a solution that fits scope and budget constraints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Financial Independence Course</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/writing-financial-independence-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 14:21:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/writing-financial-independence-course/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve been following us for a while, you know we are super passionate about FIRE/financial independence.
Five years ago, we didn&amp;rsquo;t even know where our money was going. Our dream of moving abroad felt so far away: we didn&amp;rsquo;t have any money. But we knew we had to do something about it!
We made a promise: that we would never have problems with money anymore.
We started budgeting, investing, and growing our net worth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
