<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>software development on hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/software-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software development on hexdevs</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.hexdevs.com/images/opengraph/hexdevs_logo.png</url>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/images/opengraph/hexdevs_logo.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 14:44:02 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building Technical Wealth and Improving Legacy Code with M. Scott Ford</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/building-technical-wealth-legacy-code-m-scott-ford/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 14:44:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/building-technical-wealth-legacy-code-m-scott-ford/</guid>
      <description>Are you working on Ruby on Rails Applications that are constantly on fire, overwhelmed by technical debt? What if you were building Technical Wealth instead? Learn which tools &amp;amp; strategies to work with legacy code effectively, remove dead code, and leave tech debt behind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Surprising Way to Become a Senior Software Developer with Caroline Salib</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/get-to-senior-developer-caroline-salib/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 18:06:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/get-to-senior-developer-caroline-salib/</guid>
      <description>What to do when you&amp;#39;ve been doing one technical course after the other, and still not making the jump to Senior? What are the non-obvious skills you need to be promoted to Senior? Listen to our conversation with Caroline Salib on how to identify the non-obvious skills to get promoted to Senior Software Developer -- and it&amp;#39;s not another technical course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Ruby Developers Don’t Ask for Advice. They Do This And Build A Reputation As a Result</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/smart-ruby-developers-dont-ask-for-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 12:48:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/smart-ruby-developers-dont-ask-for-advice/</guid>
      <description>Want to find out for sure whether you’re moving up the Engineering Ladder anytime soon or not? Instead of asking for advice, ask for Instructive Feedback. Here&amp;#39;s how.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find your Ruby Software Career Path with Mina Slater</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-software-engineer-career-path-mina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 16:40:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-software-engineer-career-path-mina/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever reflected on your career goals as a Software Developer? How often do you talk with someone who’s doing the kind of work you want to be doing? Find out how Mina Slater created her own role by taking advantage of her theater management background and expanding the impact of her work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 1 Mistake Keeping Mid-Career Developers Stuck in a Loop</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/one-mistake-keeping-mid-level-developers-stuck-in-a-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 10:59:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/one-mistake-keeping-mid-level-developers-stuck-in-a-loop/</guid>
      <description>Are you stuck as a mid-level developer? Trying to keep practicing after work, but don&amp;#39;t feel like you&amp;#39;re learning anything? What if you knew the next steps for you to make the jump to Senior? Learn how to save time and energy by doing one thing differently today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unhappy as a Developer? How Not To Be Miserable with Dr. Randy Paterson</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unhappy-software-developers-randy-paterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 16:25:06 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unhappy-software-developers-randy-paterson/</guid>
      <description>Do you suffer from Slack notification anxiety? On-call schedules and deadlines giving you nightmares? Learn how to deal with conflict at work and in relationships with Dr. Randy Paterson, author of The Assertiveness Workbook.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
