<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software development on hexdevs</title>
    <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/software-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software development on hexdevs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 12:48:27 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hexdevs.com/tags/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Smart Ruby Developers Don’t Ask for Advice. They Do This And Build A Reputation As a Result</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/smart-ruby-developers-dont-ask-for-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 12:48:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/smart-ruby-developers-dont-ask-for-advice/</guid>
      <description>If you could run a career quality tool to analyze your progress, would it say you’re moving in the right direction? What score would you get?
Here’s the catch: how you think you’re doing and what your teammates think how you&amp;rsquo;re doing are not the same thing.
Want to find out for sure whether you’re moving up the Engineering Ladder anytime soon or not? The only way is by asking for instructive feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to find your Ruby Software Career Path with Mina Slater</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-software-engineer-career-path-mina/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 16:40:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/ruby-software-engineer-career-path-mina/</guid>
      <description>Often as developers, we believe we are supposed to know everything. Just figure everything by ourselves. As long as we get faster and better at coding, our careers will progress smoothly.
But if you ask around, you’ll notice that most people are feeling technically stuck, despite years of experience. If you ask for career advice, people will throw you an endless list of complex technical skills to master.
That’s not what you’ll find here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 1 Mistake Keeping Mid-Career Developers Stuck in a Loop</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/one-mistake-keeping-mid-level-developers-stuck-in-a-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 10:59:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/one-mistake-keeping-mid-level-developers-stuck-in-a-loop/</guid>
      <description>You look at the clock: it&amp;rsquo;s 5 PM.
You&amp;rsquo;ve been sitting on a chair for the past ~8 hours&amp;hellip; Or worse: just endless, mind-numbing meetings all day. No wonder why you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like opening up a technical book or watching tutorials after work.
Even so, you try to push yourself one more time because you want to keep growing in your career.
You try to finish one exercise from the latest technical material you’ve invested in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unhappy as a Developer? How Not To Be Miserable with Dr. Randy Paterson</title>
      <link>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unhappy-software-developers-randy-paterson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 16:25:06 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hexdevs.com/posts/unhappy-software-developers-randy-paterson/</guid>
      <description>Do you suffer from Slack notification anxiety? On-call schedules and deadlines giving you nightmares? Are your teammates nitpicking your code during code review?
Instead of quitting your job out of frustration and having to go through another round of technical interviews, what if you knew how to have a great relationship with your work?
Learn how to deal with imposter syndrome, unrealistic deadlines, and stop communicating passive-aggressively today! Communicate effectively with your team and finish the day feeling good about what you&amp;rsquo;ve accomplished.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
